Graphic/Web Designer

# **Qualification Profile**

Creative and aesthetically inclined graphic and web designer with 5+ years of success managing art and graphics of promotional products aimed at building corporate identity, fostering brand awareness, and establishing multifaceted brand guidelines. Demonstrated success designing, developing, and launching visually appealing and responsive websites with a keen focus on achieving defined goals. Strong visual acuity coupled with analytic ability to translate business goals and strategies into coordinated and compelling messages. Instrumental in creating guiding creative process and maintaining strong relations with clients through exceptional communication skills.

# **Educational Background**

Master of Fine Arts in Digital and Interdisciplinary Art Practice The City College of New York New York, NY

Bachelor of Fine Arts in Film/Cinema/Video Studies Pratt Institute Brooklyn, NY

# **Professional Training**

**Certificate Program Full Stack Web Development**, University of
Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA

## **Technical Proficiencies**

#### **Coding**

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Front-end Development, SQL, Cloud Computing

#### Design

Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, XD

#### **Productivity Software**

Microsoft Office, Slack, Conference calling software, Evernote, Google Drive

## **Areas of Expertise**

- Creative Project Management
- Graphic & Web Design
- Customer & Technical Support
- Website Design & Improvement
- Print & Marketing Materials Design
- Branding & Marketing Communications
- Documentation & Reporting
- Client Relationship Management

# **Professional Experience**

#### Fireball Printing, Philadelphia, PA Project Administrator

2016 - 2020

Managed complete lifecycle of various print projects from inception to completion aimed at achieving project within agreed timelines and budgetary constraints while meeting clients' expectations and resolving concerns in an efficient manner. Created tickets (blueprint) for whole project that followed down line by various teams for project execution. Maintained consistent collaboration with actual designers as well as ensured accurate projects processing.

- Contributed to delivering framework for production of printed materials by generating instructional tickets.
- Utilized quality communication skills to ensure seamless communication between multiple production departments while working in a fast-paced, deadline-oriented environment.

## PhotoLounge, Philadelphia, PA Customer Support Specialist

2015 - 2016

Ensured successful orders and smooth operations of storefront by managing dialogues between customers and production staff.

 Played an anchored role in streamlining technical operations for clients in fast paced photo lab environment.

# The City College of New York, New York, NY Adjunct Lecturer

2014 - 2015

Delivered quality guidance and direction to students as well as orchestrated problemsolving workshops related to technical workflow in Photoshop and creative process.

- Enhanced undergraduate students' skillset regarding Adobe Suite and topics in contemporary art through lectures.
- Lectured multiple courses, including Computer Imaging and Illustration (ART 29526) as well as Photography and Visual Perception (ART 10410).

# **Key Projects**

### Fridge For All | ffa-ks.herokuapp.com | GitHub

Developed application where registered users can contribute to the inventory of a community fridge, thus making sure what's most needed will be donated.

- Tools: HTML, CSS/Bootstrap, JavaScript, Node.js, Express.js, Axios, React.
- Role: Maintained consistent collaboration with Meredith Jones and Luke Martin.

#### Dungeon Master Manager | obscure-sea-50010.herokuapp.com | GitHub

A full stack application to help you manage organize your adventures as a dungeon master.

- **Tools:** HTML, CSS/Bootstrap, JavaScript, Node.js, Express.js, MySql, Heroku, Passport/Bcrypt.
- Role: Collaboration with John Hauth, Brandon Grayson, and Merlin Rock.

#### Plant Scout | karajsch.github.io/plant-scout | GitHub

A simple app where users can search for plants and save them to their local storage while receiving information about weather conditions.

- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, GoogleFonts, and Trefle API.
- Role: Maintained consistent collaboration with Gregory Leighton and Tamira Bell.